Guide to the Alice Mary Baldwin Papers, 1863 - 1961
Duke University. University Archives
- Alphabetical Files, 1924-1958
  - Duke University
    - Woman's College
      - Programs, 1938-1941, [undated] (Box 12, Folder 135)
      - Social Regulations, 1930-1944, [undated] (Box 12, Folder 136)
      - Student Forum Committee, 1934-1948 (Box 12, Folder 137)
      - Student Publications, 1931 (Box 12, Folder 138)
    - Woman's Student Government Association
      - 1924-1939 (Box 12, Folder 139)
      - 1940-1947, [undated] (Box 12, Folder 140)
    - Young Men's Christian Association, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 141)
  - Duke University Church, 1946-1947, [undated] (Box 12, Folder 142)
  - Durham, N.C., Girls Guardian Club, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 143)
  - English Speaking Union, 1940-1941 (Box 12, Folder 144)
  - Ewha College, Seoul, Korea, 1935-1947, [undated] (Box 12, Folder 145)
  - Gilbert, Katherine Everett, [undated] (Box 13, Folder 146)
  - Historical Society of North Carolina, 1940-1946 (Box 13, Folder 147)
  - Institute of Women's Professional Relations, 1927-1944 (Box 13, Folder 148)
  - International Student Service, 1938-1941 (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - League of Nations Association, 1931-1932 (Box 13, Folder 150)
  - League of Women Voters
    - Correspondence, 1926-1934, [undated] (Box 13, Folder 151)
    - Clippings and Other Materials, 1932-1934, [undated] (Box 13, Folder 152)
  - National Association of Deans of Women
    - 1926-1937 (Box 13, Folder 153)
    - 1938-1947, [undated] (Box 13, Folder 154)
  - National Vocational Guidance Association, 1939, [undated] (Box 13, Folder 155)
  - North Carolina Association of Deans of Women
    - 1924-1929 (Box 13, Folder 156)
    - 1930-1942 (Box 13, Folder 157)
    - [undated] (Box 13, Folder 158)
  - North Carolina College Conference, 1939-1946, [undated] (Box 14, Folder 159)
  - North Carolina Council of Women in Education, 1930-1932, [undated] (Box 14, Folder 160)
  - North Carolina Education Association, 1942 (Box 14, Folder 161)
  - North Carolina State Art Society, 1942-1949 (Box 14, Folder 162)
  - North Carolina State Forum Committee, 1938-1939, [undated] (Box 14, Folder 163)
  - North Carolina Unemployment Compensation Commission, 1941-1943, [undated] (Box 14, Folder 164)
  - North Carolina Vocational Guidance Association
    - 1937 (Box 14, Folder 165)
    - January, 1938-April, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 166)
    - May, 1938-December, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 167)
    - January, 1939-May, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 168)
    - June, 1938-December, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 169)
    - 1940-1947 (Box 14, Folder 170)
    - [undated] (Box 14, Folder 171)
  - Nursery Schools, 1954, [undated] (Box 15, Folder 172)
  - Peoples Mandate to End War, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 173)
  - Personnel Associations, 1945-1946, [undated] (Box 15, Folder 174)
  - Personnel File [RESTRICTED - Personnel records]
    - 1924-1939 (Box 15, Folder 175)
    - 1940-1947, [undated] (Box 15, Folder 176)
  - Pi Gamma Mu, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 177)
  - Placemats and Napkins, 1939-1947 (Box 15, Folder 178)
  - Presbyterian Church Circle, [undated] (Box 15, Folder 179)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 1932-1946, [undated] (Box 15, Folder 180)
  - Southern Association of Colleges for Women, 1934-1946 (Box 15, Folder 181)
  - Southern Conference for Human Welfare, 1945-1946 (Box 15, Folder 182)
  - Southern School for Workers
    - Correspondence
      - 1928-1940 (Box 15, Folder 183)
      - 1941-1947 (Box 16, Folder 184)
    - Other Materials
      - 1927-1932 (Box 16, Folder 185)
      - 1933-1935 (Box 16, Folder 186)
      - 1936-1938 (Box 16, Folder 187)
      - 1939-1940 (Box 16, Folder 188)
      - 1941-1942 (Box 16, Folder 189)
      - 1944-1948, [undated] (Box 17, Folder 190)
  - State Literary and Historical Association of North Carolina, 1944-1948, [undated] (Box 17, Folder 191)
  - Student Term Papers
    - 1929-1930 (Box 17, Folder 192)
    - 1932,1939 (Box 17, Folder 193)
  - United Services Organizations, Durham, N.C., 1944-1946, [undated] (Box 17, Folder 194)
  - U.S. Federal Works Agency, Works Projects Administration, 1940-1942, [undated] (Box 17, Folder 195)
  - U.S. Navy Waves
    - Correspondence
      - June, 1942-August, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 196)
      - September, 1942-June, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 197)
      - July, 1943-April, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 198)
      - May, 1944-February, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 199)
    - Photographs, circa 1940s (Box 18, Folder 200)
    - Photograph album, circa 1940s (Box 18, Folder 201)
    - Print Materials, circa 1940s (Box 18, Folder 202)
    - Clippings, circa 1940s (Box 18, Folder 203)
    - Other Materials, circa 1940s (Box 18, Folder 204-205)
  - Women's Action Committee for Victory and Lasting Peace, 1943-1944 (Box 18, Folder 206)
  - World Center for Women's Archives, 1938-1939 (Box 18, Folder 207)
  - World Federalists of North Carolina, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 208)
  - Young Women's Christian Association, 1939-1947 (Box 18, Folder 209)
- Writings, 1902-1960
  The Writings series consists of Baldwin's own articles and essays, as well as her notes, drafts, and related materials. Most of her writings focused on the colonial United States, especially colonial clergy, and higher education for women. Her ninety-page essay, "The Woman's College As I Remember It," documents Baldwin's challenges in administering Duke's Woman's College. The series begins with individual essays and articles, organized alphabetically, followed by other writing-related materials, organized alphabetically by type (i.e. notes, book reviews, etc.).
  - "The Development and Place of the Co-Ordinate College," [undated] (Box 18, Folder 210)
  - "Gustavus III of Sweden: a Study of the Enlightened Despotism of the Eighteenth Century in Europe," [draft of Masters Thesis, with notes], 1902 (Box 18, Folder 211)
  - "Gustavus III of Sweden," [draft of Masters Thesis, undated] (Box 19, Folder 212)
  - "History of the North Carolina Division of the American Association of University Women, 1947-1957," [undated] (Box 19, Folder 213)
  - "The Influence of Religious Liberalism on the American Revolution," December, 1921 (Box 19, Folder 214)
  - "The Influence of the New England Clergy upon American Constitutional Doctrine," [Abstract of Ph.D. dissertation, undated] (Box 19, Folder 215)
  - "The Ministers of the Gospel in Revolutionary Days," August, 1922 (Box 19, Folder 216)
  - "My Retirement" [undated] (Box 19, Folder 217)
  - "The Political Theories of Some of the 'New Lights': Presbyterian Clergy of Virginia and North Carolina," [handwritten, undated] (Box 19, Folder 218)
  - "The Political Theories of Some of the 'New Lights': Presbyterian Clergy of Virginia and North Carolina," [typed, undated] (Box 19, Folder 219)
  - "The Reading of Women in the Colonies Before 1750"
    - Draft, [undated] (Box 19, Folder 220)
    - Draft, 1960 [Folder 1 of 2. Located in Oversized Materials, Box 24] (Box 19)
    - Draft, 1960 [Folder 2 of 2] (Box 19, Folder 221)
    - Notes, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 222-223)
    - Notes, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 224-226)
  - "Twenty-Five Years of the Woman's College at Duke University," [multiple drafts, undated] (Box 20, Folder 227)
  - Untitled Paper, [undated, appears to be draft of "Two Sisters of Old Boston"] (Box 20, Folder 228)
  - "Two Sisters of Old Boston," [undated, with notes] (Box 20, Folder 229)
  - "Two Sisters of Old Boston," [undated] (Box 20, Folder 230)
  - "The Woman's College as I Remember It," 1959 (Box 20, Folder 231)
  - "The Woman's College as I Remember It," [draft, undated] (Box 20, Folder 232)
  - "The Woman's College as I Remember It," [draft, undated. Located in Oversized Materials, Box 24] (Box 20)
  - "The Woman's College as I Remember It," notes, preface, 1960 (Box 21, Folder 233)
  - "The Woman's College as I Remember It," notes [located in Oversized Materials, Box 24] (Box 21)
  - Articles, 1934, 1936, [undated] (Box 21, Folder 234)
  - Articles, [undated] (Box 21, Folder 235)
  - Book Reviews and Articles, circa 1920s-1940s (Box 21, Folder 236)
  - Book Reviews, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 21, Folder 237)
  - Notes, [undated] (Box 21, Folder 238-239)
  - Outline for Course, [undated] (Box 21, Folder 240)
  - Poems, [undated] (Box 21, Folder 241)
  - Untitled, 1921 [Located in Oversized Materials, Box 24] (Box 21)
- Speeches and Addresses
  The Speeches and Addresses series consists of the notecards Baldwin used when making presentations. Most of the cards are undated.
  - 1921-1926 (Box 21, Folder 242)
  - 1930-1932 (Box 21, Folder 243)
  - 1933-1935 (Box 22, Folder 244)
  - 1936-1939 (Box 22, Folder 245)
  - 1940-1941 (Box 22, Folder 246)
  - 1942-1946 (Box 22, Folder 247)
  - 1950-1954 (Box 22, Folder 248)
  - [Undated] (Box 22, Folder 249-253)
- Printed Material
  The Printed Material series contains both personal and professional bound volumes and pamphlets. Several items are dedicated to Baldwin, and others were simply materials used by Baldwin in her administrative work or research. Materials are organized alphabetically.
  - "The Baldwin Annual" of the Baldwin School, dedicated to Alice M. Baldwin, 1913, [Located in Oversized Materials, Box 25] (Box 22)
  - Book Review Reprints, 1949-1950, [undated] (Box 22, Folder 254)
  - "Concerning Sororities," 1938, 1941 (Box 22, Folder 255)
  - "Illiterature Part Two," by George and Helen Young, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 256)
  - National Panhellenic Congress booklets, 1925-1938 (Box 22, Folder 257)
  - New World of the Mind, by J.B. Rhine, signed by the author to Dr. Alice Baldwin, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 258)
  - Old Testament Stories, Comically Illustrated, inscribed to Miss Alice M. Baldwin from Samuel F. Mordecai on March 17, 1924, and later sent to Dr. Flowers by Baldwin (Box 23, Folder 259)
  - Documentation accompanying Old Testament Stories, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 260)
  - "Prelude to Independence: the International Significance of the Bill of Rights," an address by Dag Hammarskjold, May 15, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 261)
  - "The United States and the Far East," regional conference by the Duke American Assembly, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 262)
  - Placemat drawings of East Campus scenes (Box 23, Folder 272)
- Photographs
  The Photographs series consists of Baldwin's personal photos. Many appear to have been taken during vacations in New England and on other holidays.
  - Circa 1920s (Box 23, Folder 263-264)
  - Circa 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 265)
  - Album [undated, appears to be photographs of family, friends, and vacations. Located in Oversized Materials, Box 25] (Box 23)
  - Album, "Photographs from England, Scotland, France, Switzerland, and Germany," [undated. Located in Oversized Materials, Box 25] (Box 23)
- Clippings, circa 1920s-1950s
  This brief series consists of clippings about Baldwin herself as well as about major topics of interest to Baldwin, such as church, labor, and prohibition. Many clippings are undated.
  - Alice Mary Baldwin, circa 1920s-1940s (Box 23, Folder 266)
  - Alice Mary Baldwin, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 23, Folder 267)
  - Church, circa 1929-1933 (Box 23, Folder 268)
  - Labor, 1929 (Box 23, Folder 269)
  - Prohibition, circa 1929-1933 (Box 23, Folder 270)
  - General, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 23, Folder 271)
- Artifacts
  The Artifacts series contains three small items, two of which are pins from Baldwin's memberships in honors societies, Phi Beta Kappa and Delta Kappa Gamma. The third item is a key presented to Baldwin by the White Duchy, a Duke secret society for women.
  - Delta Kappa Gamma pin (Box 24)
  - Phi Beta Kappa pin (Box 24)
  - White Duchy key (Box 24)
- Oversized Materials
  Oversized materials are separated from other materials simply because of their size. Each item listed in this series is also referred to in one in the previous series.
  - Untitled [writings], 1921 (Box 24)
  - "The Reading of Women in the Colonies Before 1750" draft, 1960 [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 24)
  - "The Woman's College as I Remember It," [draft, undated] (Box 24)
  - "The Woman's College as I Remember It," notes (Box 24)
  - "The Baldwin Annual" of the Baldwin School, dedicated to Alice M. Baldwin, 1913 (Box 25)
  - Album [undated, appears to be photographs of family, friends, and vacations] (Box 25)
  - Album, "Photographs from England, Scotland, France, Switzerland, and Germany," [undated] (Box 25)
  - Placemat drawings of East Campus scenes (Mc 7)
Related Material
Records of the Woman's College
Duke University Archives